<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Compare Sleep</title>
	<atom:link href="http://api.sleepnumber.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://api.sleepnumber.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 01:46:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/cropped-Sleep_Number_logo_May_2017-1-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Compare Sleep</title>
	<link>http://api.sleepnumber.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Two die in Padma river boat capsize</title>
		<link>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/two-die-in-padma-river-boat-capsize/</link>
					<comments>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/two-die-in-padma-river-boat-capsize/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 01:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://api.sleepnumber.com/?p=41</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A teenager and a child died as a boat carrying 40 passengers sank in a tributary of Padma River near Hasail in Tongibari upazila of the district after a collision with a bulkhead on Saturday. The deceased were Sifa Akhter, 15, daughter of Nazrul Bepari of Mandra village and Fahija Akhter, 6, daughter of Faruk ... <a title="Two die in Padma river boat capsize" class="read-more" href="http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/two-die-in-padma-river-boat-capsize/" aria-label="More on Two die in Padma river boat capsize">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A teenager and a child died as a boat carrying 40 passengers sank in a tributary of Padma River near Hasail in Tongibari upazila of the district after a collision with a bulkhead on Saturday.</p>
<p>The deceased were Sifa Akhter, 15, daughter of Nazrul Bepari of Mandra village and Fahija Akhter, 6, daughter of Faruk Hossain of Fatullah in Narayanganj.</p>
<p><a class="jw_media_holder media_image alignfull pop-media-holder pop-active"><span class="jw_media_caption"><span class="tt">The image shows people gathering at a ghat after a boat carrying 40 passengers sank in a tributary of Padma River near Hasail in Tongibari upazila of Munshiganj after a collision with a bulkhead on Saturday, December 16, 2023. Photo: BSS</span></span></a></p>
<p>Locals said the Hasail Bazar-bound Kheya boat capsized in the river after hitting the bulkhead in the dark while it was coming from Miah Bari ghat of Hasail char.</p>
<p>After visiting the spot, Tongibari Upazila Nirbahi Officer (UNO) Aslam Hossain said many passengers swam ashore after the incident.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/two-die-in-padma-river-boat-capsize/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hostages killed by Israel forces waved white flag</title>
		<link>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/hostages-killed-by-israel-forces-waved-white-flag/</link>
					<comments>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/hostages-killed-by-israel-forces-waved-white-flag/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 01:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://api.sleepnumber.com/?p=38</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Israeli army said that three hostages mistakenly killed by soldiers carried a white flag and cried for help in Hebrew on Saturday. An army official said the hostages were all &#8220;without shirts&#8221; and had &#8220;a stick with a white cloth on it&#8221;, but a soldier felt threatened and opened fire. Yotam Haim, Alon Shamriz ... <a title="Hostages killed by Israel forces waved white flag" class="read-more" href="http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/hostages-killed-by-israel-forces-waved-white-flag/" aria-label="More on Hostages killed by Israel forces waved white flag">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli army said that three hostages mistakenly killed by soldiers carried a white flag and cried for help in Hebrew on Saturday.</p>
<p>An army official said the hostages were all &#8220;without shirts&#8221; and had &#8220;a stick with a white cloth on it&#8221;, but a soldier felt threatened and opened fire.</p>
<p>Yotam Haim, Alon Shamriz and Samer El-Talalqa all in their 20s were shot during operations in Gaza City on Friday, sparking protests in Israel.</p>
<p>They were among about 250 people taken hostage during Palestinian group Hamas&#8217;s October 7 campaign in Israel, which killed around 1,140 people, mostly civilians, according to Israeli figures.</p>
<p>Vowing to destroy Hamas and bring back the hostages, Israel launched a massive military offensive against the Palestinians that has left much of the Gaza Strip in ruins. The territory&#8217;s Hamas government says the war has killed at least 18,800 people, mostly women and children.</p>
<p>Army spokesman Daniel Hagari said that during fighting in the Shejaiya district of Gaza City, troops &#8220;mistakenly identified three Israeli hostages as a threat and as a result, fired toward them and the hostages were killed&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;Two are killed immediately, one is injured and runs back into the building,&#8221; the official said, adding that the soldiers heard &#8220;a cry for help in Hebrew&#8221;.</p>
<p>Despite a ceasefire order, &#8220;there&#8217;s another burst of fire towards the third figure and he also dies.&#8221;</p>
<p>The official called it a &#8220;tragic&#8221; event and &#8220;very hard day&#8221;, but said the troops had faced &#8220;intense combat in the area&#8221;.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu described their deaths as an &#8220;unbearable tragedy&#8221;.</p>
<p>Hundreds were expected to gather Saturday in Tel Aviv to call on Netanyahu&#8217;s government to secure the release of 129 hostages still held in the Hamas-ruled Gaza Strip.</p>
<p>&#8220;I am dying of fear,&#8221; said Merav Svirsky, sister of hostage Itay Svirsky at a protest on Friday. &#8220;We demand a deal now.&#8221;</p>
<p>In November, a one-week truce saw more than 100 hostages freed in exchange for Palestinians held in Israeli jails, but fighting has since resumed.</p>
<p>The hostages&#8217; deaths have heightened already fierce scrutiny of how Israel is conducting its ground and air assault in Gaza.</p>
<p>The White House, which provides billions of dollars in military aid to Israel, has voiced growing concern over civilian deaths.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&#8220;I want them to be focused on how to save civilian lives &#8212; not stop going after Hamas, but be more careful,&#8221; US President Joe Biden said this week.</p>
<p>News platform Axios said the director of Israeli intelligence agency Mossad, David Barnea, was due to meet this weekend in an unspecified location in Europe with Qatari Prime Minister Sheikh Mohammed bin Abdulrahman Al Thani, who helped negotiate the earlier truce.</p>
<p>In Gaza, fierce fighting continued.</p>
<p>The Israeli army said Saturday it had raided two schools in Gaza City. It said they were Hamas hiding places.</p>
<p>A funeral was held in Gaza for Samer Abu Daqqa, a journalist with TV network Al Jazeera killed the previous day by an Israeli strike in Khan Yunis that also wounded his colleague, Wael al-Dahdouh.</p>
<p>&#8220;He died hungry, they died with nothing to eat, with hunger. Oh my darling,&#8221; said his grieving mother, Umm Maher.</p>
<p>More than 60 journalists and media staff have died since the war began, according to the Committee to Protect Journalists.</p>
<p>&#8220;We were reporting, we were filming, we had finished and we were with the civil defense, but when we were on the way back, they hit us with a missile,&#8221; said Dahdouh, who lost his wife, two children and grandchild earlier in the war.</p>
<p>In the face of growing international pressure, Israel announced a &#8220;temporary measure&#8221; allowing aid to be delivered directly to Gaza through the Kerem Shalom border crossing.</p>
<p>A World Health Organization representative said the decision was &#8220;very good news&#8221;.</p>
<p>Since the war began, aid has trickled into Gaza through the Rafah crossing with Egypt.</p>
<p>Humanitarian agencies have said the volume is just a fraction of what is needed to help the estimated 1.9 million Gazans displaced by the war.</p>
<p>Washington hopes the Palestinian Authority can resume control of Gaza as part of a renewed push for a two-state solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict &#8212; a solution that Netanyahu has resolutely opposed.</p>
<p>The conflict has appeared to push any peace deal further out of view.</p>
<p>Multiple Western governments issued a joint statement demanding that Israel &#8220;take concrete steps to halt unprecedented violence by Israeli settlers&#8221; in the West Bank.</p>
<p>More than 280 Palestinians have been killed by Israeli forces or settlers in the West Bank since the war in Gaza erupted.</p>
<p>Israel&#8217;s police force said it had suspended several officers after they severely assaulted a journalist for Turkish news agency Anadolu as he was trying to take photos of Palestinians praying in annexed east Jerusalem.</p>
<p>And on Saturday eight Palestinians were arrested across the West Bank during Israeli raids, according to Palestinian news agency Wafa.<br />
The war continues to be felt across the Middle East, with fears of a new front opening on Israel&#8217;s northern border with Lebanon, where it has exchanged regular fire with fighters, mainly the powerful Iran-backed Hezbollah.</p>
<p>Israeli air defenses &#8220;intercepted a hostile aircraft&#8221; from Lebanon after sirens blared in the northern town of Zarit, the army said.</p>
<p>The conflict has also spilled over into vital Red Sea shipping routes.</p>
<p>A British destroyer brought down a suspected attack drone, Defence Minister Grant Shapps said Saturday.</p>
<p>Global shipping lines Maersk and Hapag-Lloyd earlier announced they were halting voyages through the area following attacks on vessels by Yemeni rebels allied with Hamas.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/hostages-killed-by-israel-forces-waved-white-flag/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Goodreads, an online platform where users can post book reviews and interact with their favourite authors, generally has a wholesome brand: it gives book lovers a place to geek out about their fandom, and can also give authors a big boost in publicity.  But when anything gets as popular and powerful as Goodreads has become, it turns out there will be people who try to game the system.  This recently happened in truly bizarre fashion — and it backfired badly on one author, who lost a two-book deal with Penguin Random House.  For this Friday&#8217;s wrap panel, Jael Richardson, Syrus Marcus Ware and Sarah-Tai Black join host Elamin Abdelmahmoud to talk about the drama, as well as Julia Roberts and Mahershala Ali&#8217;s poignant Netflix thriller Leave the World Behind.</title>
		<link>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/goodreads-an-online-platform-where-users-can-post-book-reviews-and-interact-with-their-favourite-authors-generally-has-a-wholesome-brand-it-gives-book-lovers-a-place-to-geek-out-about-their-fandom/</link>
					<comments>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/goodreads-an-online-platform-where-users-can-post-book-reviews-and-interact-with-their-favourite-authors-generally-has-a-wholesome-brand-it-gives-book-lovers-a-place-to-geek-out-about-their-fandom/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 01:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://api.sleepnumber.com/?p=36</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Awami League has reached a tentative decision regarding seat distribution with its allies among the 14-party alliance for the upcoming 12th national parliamentary election. Despite discussions with its longstanding ally, Jatiya Party, a final agreement on seat allocation has yet to be reached. Due to the imminent deadline for withdrawal of nomination papers on Sunday, ... <a title="Goodreads, an online platform where users can post book reviews and interact with their favourite authors, generally has a wholesome brand: it gives book lovers a place to geek out about their fandom, and can also give authors a big boost in publicity.  But when anything gets as popular and powerful as Goodreads has become, it turns out there will be people who try to game the system.  This recently happened in truly bizarre fashion — and it backfired badly on one author, who lost a two-book deal with Penguin Random House.  For this Friday&#8217;s wrap panel, Jael Richardson, Syrus Marcus Ware and Sarah-Tai Black join host Elamin Abdelmahmoud to talk about the drama, as well as Julia Roberts and Mahershala Ali&#8217;s poignant Netflix thriller Leave the World Behind." class="read-more" href="http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/goodreads-an-online-platform-where-users-can-post-book-reviews-and-interact-with-their-favourite-authors-generally-has-a-wholesome-brand-it-gives-book-lovers-a-place-to-geek-out-about-their-fandom/" aria-label="More on Goodreads, an online platform where users can post book reviews and interact with their favourite authors, generally has a wholesome brand: it gives book lovers a place to geek out about their fandom, and can also give authors a big boost in publicity.  But when anything gets as popular and powerful as Goodreads has become, it turns out there will be people who try to game the system.  This recently happened in truly bizarre fashion — and it backfired badly on one author, who lost a two-book deal with Penguin Random House.  For this Friday&#8217;s wrap panel, Jael Richardson, Syrus Marcus Ware and Sarah-Tai Black join host Elamin Abdelmahmoud to talk about the drama, as well as Julia Roberts and Mahershala Ali&#8217;s poignant Netflix thriller Leave the World Behind.">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Awami League has reached a tentative decision regarding seat distribution with its allies among the 14-party alliance for the upcoming 12th national parliamentary election.</p>
<p>Despite discussions with its longstanding ally, Jatiya Party, a final agreement on seat allocation has yet to be reached.</p>
<p>Due to the imminent deadline for withdrawal of nomination papers on Sunday, Awami League leaders convened in two closed-door meetings on Saturday night to make a conclusive decision.</p>
<p>The initial meeting, held at the political office of the Awami League president in Dhanmondi at 5:30pm, lasted approximately an hour and a half.</p>
<p>Subsequently, the second meeting commenced at 9:30pm, followed by another session at 10:30pm. However, party representatives refrained from disclosing details about the discussions.</p>
<p>The closed-door meetings, conducted in the office secretary&#8217;s room, were presided over by the party&#8217;s general secretary, Obaidul Quader.</p>
<p>Attendees in the first meeting included Prime Minister&#8217;s Adviser on Private Industry and Investment Salman F Rahman, Awami League Organizing Secretary BM Mozammel Haque, and Mirza Azam.</p>
<p>The second meeting saw the participation of Obaidul Quader, Salman F Rahman, BM Mozammel Haque, Mirza Azam, along with party secretary Barrister Biplab Barua, information and research secretary Dr Salim Mahmud, Executive Member Mohammad A Arafat, and Deputy Secretary Sayem Khan.</p>
<p>Sources within the party disclosed that both meetings primarily focused on negotiating seat settlements with partner and allied parties.</p>
<p>Earlier, Awami League had announced its decision to allocate seven seats to its allies within the 14-party alliance.</p>
<p>However, negotiations with Jatiya Party have encountered challenges, with the latter seeking concessions in 40 seats, while Awami League is reluctant to concede more than 26 seats.</p>
<p>Ongoing discussions revolve around finding a middle ground on this matter. There have been five rounds of discussions between Awami League and Jatiya Party regarding the seat compromise.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/goodreads-an-online-platform-where-users-can-post-book-reviews-and-interact-with-their-favourite-authors-generally-has-a-wholesome-brand-it-gives-book-lovers-a-place-to-geek-out-about-their-fandom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Goodreads plot that tanked a writer&#8217;s debut</title>
		<link>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/the-goodreads-plot-that-tanked-a-writers-debut/</link>
					<comments>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/the-goodreads-plot-that-tanked-a-writers-debut/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 01:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://api.sleepnumber.com/?p=34</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Goodreads, an online platform where users can post book reviews and interact with their favourite authors, generally has a wholesome brand: it gives book lovers a place to geek out about their fandom, and can also give authors a big boost in publicity. But when anything gets as popular and powerful as Goodreads has become, it turns out there ... <a title="The Goodreads plot that tanked a writer&#8217;s debut" class="read-more" href="http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/the-goodreads-plot-that-tanked-a-writers-debut/" aria-label="More on The Goodreads plot that tanked a writer&#8217;s debut">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Goodreads, an online platform where users can post book reviews and interact with their favourite authors, generally has a wholesome brand: it gives book lovers a place to geek out about their fandom, and can also give authors a big boost in publicity.</p>
<p>But when anything gets as popular and powerful as Goodreads has become, it turns out there will be people who try to game the system.</p>
<p>This recently happened in truly bizarre fashion — and it backfired badly on one author, who lost a two-book deal with Penguin Random House.</p>
<p>For this Friday&#8217;s wrap panel, Jael Richardson, Syrus Marcus Ware and Sarah-Tai Black join host Elamin Abdelmahmoud to talk about the drama, as well as Julia Roberts and Mahershala Ali&#8217;s poignant Netflix thriller <em>Leave the World Behind</em>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/the-goodreads-plot-that-tanked-a-writers-debut/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mayim Bialik says she won&#8217;t be returning as Jeopardy! host</title>
		<link>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/mayim-bialik-says-she-wont-be-returning-as-jeopardy-host/</link>
					<comments>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/mayim-bialik-says-she-wont-be-returning-as-jeopardy-host/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 01:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://api.sleepnumber.com/?p=32</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mayim Bialik won&#8217;t be giving answers as a host of Jeopardy! anymore. The Big Bang Theory actor posted news of her departure on Instagram on Friday. &#8220;Sony has informed me that I will no longer be hosting the syndicated version of Jeopardy!&#8221; Bialik wrote. &#8220;I am incredibly honoured to have been nominated for a prime time Emmy for hosting ... <a title="Mayim Bialik says she won&#8217;t be returning as Jeopardy! host" class="read-more" href="http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/mayim-bialik-says-she-wont-be-returning-as-jeopardy-host/" aria-label="More on Mayim Bialik says she won&#8217;t be returning as Jeopardy! host">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mayim Bialik won&#8217;t be giving answers as a host of <em>Jeopardy!</em> anymore.</p>
<p><em>The Big Bang Theory</em> actor posted news of her departure on Instagram on Friday.</p>
<p>&#8220;Sony has informed me that I will no longer be hosting the syndicated version of <em>Jeopardy!</em>&#8221; Bialik wrote.</p>
<p>&#8220;I am incredibly honoured to have been nominated for a prime time Emmy for hosting this year and I am deeply grateful for the opportunity to have been a part of the <em>Jeopardy!</em> family.&#8221;</p>
<p>In a statement, the show said that former champion Ken Jennings, who split hosting duties with Bialik, will now be the sole host next season &#8220;to maintain continuity for our viewers.&#8221;</p>
<div>
<ul class="similarLinks">
<li class="similarListItem"><span class="similarLinkText">I recruited 3 Jeopardy! players from Vancouver to form the city&#8217;s greatest pub trivia team — and lost</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>&#8220;We are truly grateful for all of Mayim&#8217;s contributions to<em> Jeopardy!, </em>and we hope to continue to work with her on primetime specials,&#8221; the show said.</p>
<p>Bialik was the solo host for Season 1 of <em>Celebrity Jeopardy!</em>, which first aired in September 2022.</p>
<p>In May, Bialik declared her support for the Hollywood writers&#8217; strike and declined to appear on the game show. Jennings has been hosting season 40 of the syndicated show by himself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/mayim-bialik-says-she-wont-be-returning-as-jeopardy-host/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tiff Macklem says 2024 will be a transition year for economy, too soon to consider rate cuts</title>
		<link>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/tiff-macklem-says-2024-will-be-a-transition-year-for-economy-too-soon-to-consider-rate-cuts/</link>
					<comments>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/tiff-macklem-says-2024-will-be-a-transition-year-for-economy-too-soon-to-consider-rate-cuts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 01:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://api.sleepnumber.com/?p=30</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bank of Canada governor Tiff Macklem says he expects 2024 to be a transition year as higher interest rates slow down the economy, making way for lower inflation. In his final speech of the year, the governor laid out his expectations for a softer economy next year and offered criteria for the central bank to ... <a title="Tiff Macklem says 2024 will be a transition year for economy, too soon to consider rate cuts" class="read-more" href="http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/tiff-macklem-says-2024-will-be-a-transition-year-for-economy-too-soon-to-consider-rate-cuts/" aria-label="More on Tiff Macklem says 2024 will be a transition year for economy, too soon to consider rate cuts">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bank of Canada governor Tiff Macklem says he expects 2024 to be a transition year as higher interest rates slow down the economy, making way for lower inflation.</p>
<p>In his final speech of the year, the governor laid out his expectations for a softer economy next year and offered criteria for the central bank to start discussing rate cuts.</p>
<p>&#8220;The effects of past interest rate increases will continue to work through the economy, restraining spending and limit growth and employment. Unfortunately, this is what&#8217;s needed to take the remaining stream out of inflation,&#8221; Macklem&#8217;s prepared remarks read.</p>
<p>Are you trying to keep holiday costs low this year? Share your creative solutions by emailing ask@cbc.ca.<br />
However, this weakness is what will help get inflation back to target, he adds, which would in turn open the door to rate cut discussions.</p>
<p>But Macklem warns that nothing is certain and there could be bumps along the way.</p>
<p>&#8220;Once governing council is assured that we are clearly on a path back to price stability, we will be considering whether and when we can lower our policy interest rate,&#8221; Macklem said. &#8220;I know it&#8217;s tempting to rush ahead to that discussion. But it&#8217;s still too early to consider cutting our policy rate.&#8221;</p>
<p>Tiff Macklem says he&#8217;d rather raise rates too much than too little<br />
Freeland hosts annual meeting with provincial, territorial counterparts today<br />
Until then, the governor says the central bank will continue to debate whether interest rates are high enough to bring inflation down.</p>
<p>He notes that the world is experiencing increased economic volatility, which requires central banks to be nimble.</p>
<p>The Bank of Canada has opted to hold its key interest rate steady at five per cent during its last three rate decisions. Economists widely expect its next move will be a cut and come sometime next year.</p>
<p>WATCH | Tiff Macklem on what needs to happen before the central bank considers rate cuts:</p>
<p>2% inflation target in sight but &#8216;not there yet,&#8217; BoC governor says<br />
1 day ago<br />
Duration0:38<br />
In his final speech of the year, Bank of Canada governor Tiff Macklem touched on what still needs to happen before the central bank considers cutting rates. &#8216;We still need to see more downward momentum in core inflation,&#8217; he said.<br />
Macklem&#8217;s speech also reflects on the lessons the central bank learned this year, including the importance of communication.</p>
<p>To that end, the central bank is now planning to hold news conferences along with every interest rate decision, rather than only once a quarter.</p>
<p>&#8220;We want households, businesses and communities to understand the action we are taking and why. Taking questions at every decision is part of my commitment to explain our actions,&#8221; he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/tiff-macklem-says-2024-will-be-a-transition-year-for-economy-too-soon-to-consider-rate-cuts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Asylum-seeker&#8217;s death on U.K. barge has activists and residents calling for change</title>
		<link>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/asylum-seekers-death-on-u-k-barge-has-activists-and-residents-calling-for-change/</link>
					<comments>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/asylum-seekers-death-on-u-k-barge-has-activists-and-residents-calling-for-change/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 01:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://api.sleepnumber.com/?p=28</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[change The death of a man on a barge housing asylum-seekers in the U.K. proves the accommodations are inhumane and untenable, say locals and advocates. Police confirmed this week they&#8217;re investigating the &#8220;sudden death of a resident&#8221; on Bibby Stockholm, an barge housing hundreds of men on the port of Portland, England. &#8220;Something has to ... <a title="Asylum-seeker&#8217;s death on U.K. barge has activists and residents calling for change" class="read-more" href="http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/asylum-seekers-death-on-u-k-barge-has-activists-and-residents-calling-for-change/" aria-label="More on Asylum-seeker&#8217;s death on U.K. barge has activists and residents calling for change">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>change<br />
The death of a man on a barge housing asylum-seekers in the U.K. proves the accommodations are inhumane and untenable, say locals and advocates.</p>
<p>Police confirmed this week they&#8217;re investigating the &#8220;sudden death of a resident&#8221; on Bibby Stockholm, an barge housing hundreds of men on the port of Portland, England.</p>
<p>&#8220;Something has to change,&#8221; Rocca Holly-Nambi, a Portland resident who has been facilitating classes for the asylum seekers, told As It Happens host Nil Köksal.</p>
<p>&#8220;This death has cemented to us that there&#8217;s such an urgent action needed to reclaim some kind of dignity and humanity and human rights for these guys.&#8221;</p>
<p>As asylum seekers begin to call a floating barge home in the U.K., activists push back<br />
Pope Francis decries &#8216;lack of humanity&#8217; faced by migrants crossing Mediterranean<br />
In a statement, Dorset Police said they received a report of a sudden death on Tuesday, but have not released any details about who died or how.</p>
<p>&#8220;Officers are conducting inquiries into the circumstances of the incident,&#8221; the statement reads.</p>
<p>British Interior Minister James Cleverly was similarly tight-lipped when questioned in Parliament.</p>
<p>&#8220;At this stage I&#8217;m uncomfortable getting into any more details, but we will, of course, investigate fully,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Bacteria outbreak, fire exit concerns<br />
The decision to house asylum seekers on the barge — a three-storey floating accommodation anchored off the port of an island community in the British Channel — has been controversial since it was first announced in April.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s part of British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak&#8217;s strategy to crack down on asylum seekers travelling to the U.K. via the Channel, while saving money on housing those who have already arrived and are waiting to have their refugee claims heard.</p>
<p>Refugee rights organizations have decried it as inhumane, and locals initially protested the sudden arrival of hundreds into their small community.</p>
<p>Uniformed police officers stand outside on a gray day next to some stairs and a van.<br />
Police remove a gurney, thought to be carrying the deceased, off the barge on Tuesday. (Finnbarr Webster/Getty Images)<br />
Built to house 222 people, the British government has insisted the barge has a capacity to hold 500. At the moment, about 300 men reside there, according to the Guardian newspaper.</p>
<p>A local firefighters&#8217; union has called it a &#8220;potential deathtrap&#8221; due to possible overcrowding and a lack of fire exits. The British Home Office says it successfully completed health, fire, and safety checks before opening.</p>
<p>It was also briefly evacuated in August after legionella bacteria, which can cause serious illness or death, was discovered in its water supply.</p>
<p>&#8216;Suicidal intentions&#8217; and a lack of dignity<br />
Holly-Nambi says she doesn&#8217;t know any details about the person who died, but says she&#8217;s heard from men who live on the vessel that it&#8217;s &#8220;incredibly restrictive&#8221; and &#8220;quite claustrophobic.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;When you&#8217;ve come so far to escape violence and escape danger or peril or whatever it is, and then you arrive somewhere, and even then, you&#8217;re not given the dignity of [living on] land, that&#8217;s really painful and messy,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>A rectangular red and gray building with small windows set atop a barge floating beside ship dock.<br />
Built in 1976, the Bibby Stockholm barge was converted into an accommodation barge in 1992. It has previously been used as a homeless shelter, migrant detention centre and temporary accommodation for construction workers. (Toby Melville/Reuters)<br />
Steve Smith, CEO of the refugee crisis charity Care4Calais, says that since people moved onto the barge, his organization has received several reports of &#8220;suicidal intentions amongst residents,&#8221; but the government has failed to take action.</p>
<p>&#8220;This can no longer continue. Asylum seekers are human beings, many of whom have experienced the worst traumas imaginable through war, torture and persecution,&#8221; Smith said.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s time our political leaders treated them as human beings, listened to the trauma they have experienced and offered them sanctuary.&#8221;</p>
<p>Residents of the barge told the Guardian newspaper that a death onboard was inevitable.</p>
<p>&#8220;The longer they keep us here, the more I can see everyone&#8217;s mental health deteriorating,&#8221; one unnamed man said.</p>
<p>Deadly shipwreck off coast of Greece just the latest disaster at sea for Pakistani migrants<br />
Canada &#8216;like a dream&#8217; for refugee who spent 6 years in Australia&#8217;s Manus Island camp<br />
Holly-Nambi said the tragedy has brought the Portland community together in mourning, with people stopping by Bibby Stockholm to lay flowers and pay their respects.</p>
<p>&#8220;All sides of the community, from what I&#8217;m witnessing, are filled with compassion and sorrow for this loss of life,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>They are allowed to leave the barge, but are dependant on bus schedules, must pass through security checks and are restricted on what they can bring in and out of the facility, including food. That makes it hard to be away for any extended period of time, Holly-Nambi said, because most can&#8217;t afford to eat out.</p>
<p>Still, because they are integrating into the community, she says many residents who were initially opposed to having them in town have had a change of heart.</p>
<p>&#8220;When we first heard that the barge was going to arrive, there was widespread shock, anger, confusion and, I think, overall a sense that this community has been undermined by a complete lack of dialogue about this influx of visitors,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>&#8220;[Now] there are these glimmers and pockets of beauty and hope on the island where there&#8217;s been two-way integration, friendships have been made and new understandings are taking place.&#8221;</p>
<p>If residents had been included in the planning from the beginning, she says perhaps those earlier tensions — and this death — could have been prevented.</p>
<p>&#8220;We could have created a really powerful community dialogue about what it means to host people, what it means to invite people and to share and to learn.&#8221;</p>
<p>With files from The Associated Press and Reuters. Interview with Rocca Holly-Nambi produced by Leslie Amminson</p>
<p>RELATED STORIES<br />
U.K. plans to house asylum seekers on barge, amid efforts to deter boat crossings<br />
Search for 300 migrants reported missing in Atlantic shows difficulty of locating lost ships<br />
5 dead, including 4 children, in migrant boat incidents near Greece, Turkey<br />
As violence surges in Rohingya camps, victims have no path to justice<br />
Bangladesh is moving 100,000 Rohingya refugees to a cyclone-prone island made of silt<br />
How a plan to welcome 100 Syrian refugees divided a town and changed one woman&#8217;s life<br />
Doctor condemns Australia for restricting medical evacuations for refugees detained offshore</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/asylum-seekers-death-on-u-k-barge-has-activists-and-residents-calling-for-change/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canadian skier Stefanie Fleckenstein injured in crash at World Cup downhill event</title>
		<link>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/canadian-skier-stefanie-fleckenstein-injured-in-crash-at-world-cup-downhill-event/</link>
					<comments>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/canadian-skier-stefanie-fleckenstein-injured-in-crash-at-world-cup-downhill-event/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 01:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://api.sleepnumber.com/?p=26</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jasmine Flury claimed only her second World Cup win as the Swiss skier triumphed on Saturday in Val d&#8217;Isere, France, in a downhill race that was delayed because of a horrific crash for Canada&#8217;s Stefanie Fleckenstein. The race was interrupted for about 20 minutes so Fleckenstein could be treated and stretchered off the course. The ... <a title="Canadian skier Stefanie Fleckenstein injured in crash at World Cup downhill event" class="read-more" href="http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/canadian-skier-stefanie-fleckenstein-injured-in-crash-at-world-cup-downhill-event/" aria-label="More on Canadian skier Stefanie Fleckenstein injured in crash at World Cup downhill event">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jasmine Flury claimed only her second World Cup win as the Swiss skier triumphed on Saturday in Val d&#8217;Isere, France, in a downhill race that was delayed because of a horrific crash for Canada&#8217;s Stefanie Fleckenstein.</p>
<p>The race was interrupted for about 20 minutes so Fleckenstein could be treated and stretchered off the course.</p>
<p>The skier from Whistler, B.C., crashed right at the end of her run and slid over the finishing line, yelling in pain.</p>
<p>Other athletes covered their eyes and ears as Fleckenstein&#8217;s screams of agony could be clearly heard.</p>
<p>WATCH | Canadian skier crashes at finish line *Graphic content warning*:</p>
<p>Canada’s Stefanie Fleckenstein suffers major injury at World Cup downhill race, GRAPHIC WARNING.<br />
13 hours ago<br />
Duration0:36<br />
A bad crash at the finish line saw Stefanie Fleckenstein of Whistler, B.C., suffer a left leg injury and need to be taken away on a stretcher Saturday during the women&#8217;s World Cup downhill race.<br />
Flury was 0.22 seconds ahead of compatriot Joana Haehlen and 0.24 faster than Austrian skier Cornelia Huetter.</p>
<p>Flury&#8217;s only other World Cup win in her career was a super-G in her native Switzerland six years ago although the 30-year-old recorded a surprise victory in the world championships in February.</p>
<p>Sofia Goggia moved to the top of the discipline standings in the absence of Mikaela Shiffrin.</p>
<p>Standout downhill racer Goggia, who admitted afterward that she was far from her best form, was fourth, 0.44 behind Flury after a mistake in the second part of the O.K. course, which is named after French skiing greats Henri Oreiller and Jean-Claude Killy.</p>
<p>Weather forces cancellation of World Cup men&#8217;s, women&#8217;s alpine ski races<br />
Goggia nevertheless moved into the discipline lead. The Italian, who has topped the World Cup downhill standings in each of the past three seasons, has 17 more points than Flury and 20 more than Huetter.</p>
<p>Shiffrin, who won the only other downhill so far this season last week, is 30 points behind Goggia. The American is selective picking her downhills — to fit a race and training schedule that prioritizes slalom and giant slalom — and opted to skip Saturday&#8217;s race.</p>
<p>With files from CBC Sports</p>
<p>CBC&#8217;s Journalistic Standards and Practices|About CBC Sports<br />
Corrections and clarifications|Report error<br />
RELATED STORIES<br />
Weather forces cancellation of World Cup men&#8217;s, women&#8217;s alpine ski races<br />
Mikaela Shiffrin races to rare win in World Cup downhill<br />
Sofia Goggia wins 1st speed race of weather-hit World Cup ski season in super-G<br />
Alpine Canada hoping Tremblant World Cup becomes fixture after successful weekend<br />
Val Grenier 6th in giant slalom on Mont-Tremblant mountain where she learned to ski<br />
Mont-Tremblant World Cup &#8216;a dream come true&#8217; for local favourite Valerie Grenier<br />
Italy&#8217;s Brignone wins World Cup giant slalom, Shiffrin finishes 3rd in Mont-Tremblant, Que.<br />
More alpine skiing coverage</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/canadian-skier-stefanie-fleckenstein-injured-in-crash-at-world-cup-downhill-event/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joy Drop: 81-year-old goalie an inspiration to all</title>
		<link>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/joy-drop-81-year-old-goalie-an-inspiration-to-all/</link>
					<comments>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/joy-drop-81-year-old-goalie-an-inspiration-to-all/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 01:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://api.sleepnumber.com/?p=24</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Warm greetings to all my friends! As we get closer and closer to the holiday time, it&#8217;s important to reflect on things that make us happy and things that still have a lot of work in them. I feel heartened every week when my friends send me kitten videos or I find a recipe. I ... <a title="Joy Drop: 81-year-old goalie an inspiration to all" class="read-more" href="http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/joy-drop-81-year-old-goalie-an-inspiration-to-all/" aria-label="More on Joy Drop: 81-year-old goalie an inspiration to all">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Warm greetings to all my friends! As we get closer and closer to the holiday time, it&#8217;s important to reflect on things that make us happy and things that still have a lot of work in them.</p>
<p>I feel heartened every week when my friends send me kitten videos or I find a recipe. I am also buoyed by my colleagues and by my work and the places it takes me.</p>
<p>I was in Geneva last week at the United Nations and had a chance to meet some amazing people from all over the world who share a love of sports and a passion for human rights. I got to meet South African athlete Caster Semenya, and she is formidable in both her approach to life and her demeanour. I am also learning how pride and gratitude can be forms of joy in how they manifest.</p>
<p>Two women pose for a photo.<br />
Shireen Ahmed, left, and Caster Semenya. (Shireen Ahmed)<br />
An athlete who caught my attention was Gerard (Smitty) Smith from Summerside, P.E.I. The 81-year-old hockey goaltender laces up his skates and hits the ice. He has been playing in a noon-hour league since the 1980s and has a fantastic view on mobility and athleticism: &#8220;You don&#8217;t get old by playing,&#8221; he says. &#8220;You get old if you don&#8217;t play.&#8221;</p>
<p>Throughout my career, I have been awed by athletes and my interview with Leylah Fernandez was no exception. Throughout our conversation I was struck at the poise of such a thoughtful young woman. We chatted about her campaign with Ritz called The Lunchbox Moment and what it meant to be deeply connected to your culture through food. Fernandez is advocating for kids to create safe places in their lunchrooms. I was so heartened to see this initiative. As I wrote in my column, a few less-than-pleasant memories came back. But Fernandez operates with kindness and from such an accomplished star, it also reminded me to hold a sense of pride in the other love of my life: food.</p>
<p>Speaking of which, I had the great fortune of trying Happy Pops and I am blown away. These dairy-free, locally made treats, from a woman-owned business, have come into my life and I am so excited. I loved the orange and triple berry flavours but what knocked my socks off is the kulfi collection. Kulfi is a frozen dessert (like ice cream) from South Asian cultures. It&#8217;s rich and flavourful and Happy Pops nailed it. I couldn&#8217;t believe it was nut-free and dairy-free, which is not what traditional kulfi is. But it was delicious and I certainly intend to have a lot more. Their founder, Leila Keshavjee, has recently been awarded with distinctions in business and leadership.</p>
<p>When Siofra Lawless won the world junior boxing title, she was a champion. But to be championed at her school was another thing. A video of the 16-year-old being welcomed back at school went viral. It was wonderful to see her peers applaud and appreciate her.</p>
<p>A special note to the Schmidt family from Ottawa. Hannah and Jared live and train in Calgary and this week won races in Switzerland three minutes apart, the first World Cup wins for both siblings. What a proud moment for the family and the entire country.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/joy-drop-81-year-old-goalie-an-inspiration-to-all/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ontario is looking to combat lien &#8216;abuse&#8217; that&#8217;s costing some homeowners big money</title>
		<link>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/ontario-is-looking-to-combat-lien-abuse-thats-costing-some-homeowners-big-money/</link>
					<comments>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/ontario-is-looking-to-combat-lien-abuse-thats-costing-some-homeowners-big-money/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 01:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://api.sleepnumber.com/?p=22</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Abel Cheung didn&#8217;t anticipate that signing up for a simple water filter rental would end up forcing him to pay $11,000 for the privilege of refinancing his home. The Ottawa-area man rented the filter system in 2019 after being convinced by door-to-door sales representatives that it would qualify him for an energy rebate and lower ... <a title="Ontario is looking to combat lien &#8216;abuse&#8217; that&#8217;s costing some homeowners big money" class="read-more" href="http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/ontario-is-looking-to-combat-lien-abuse-thats-costing-some-homeowners-big-money/" aria-label="More on Ontario is looking to combat lien &#8216;abuse&#8217; that&#8217;s costing some homeowners big money">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Abel Cheung didn&#8217;t anticipate that signing up for a simple water filter rental would end up forcing him to pay $11,000 for the privilege of refinancing his home.</p>
<p>The Ottawa-area man rented the filter system in 2019 after being convinced by door-to-door sales representatives that it would qualify him for an energy rebate and lower his monthly bills.</p>
<p>Those savings, he said, never materialized. That turned out to be the least of his problems.</p>
<p>When Cheung went to refinance his home in 2021, he discovered a surprise roadblock. A Notice of Security Interest (NOSI) had been registered on his land title and he&#8217;d have to pay it off before going through with the financing deal.</p>
<p>&#8220;I felt really bad when I found out that I had to pay the $11,000 to clear the lien on the house,&#8221; he said. &#8220;And I feel like those companies, they can actually do these things and get away with it.&#8221;</p>
<p>The House10:09<br />
Ontario’s potential crackdown on lien scam ‘crisis’<br />
The Ontario government is trying to crack down on “bad actors” abusing a legal loophole meant to protect rental companies — that is instead seeing “crisis” levels of notices of security interest, or liens, being placed on unsuspecting property owners. The House speaks to Ontario business service minister Todd McCarthy, NDP critic Tom Rakocevic, lawyer Dennis Crawford and victims of the practice to ask if the new rules will protect consumers.<br />
A NOSI is a lien instrument meant to provide a company some assurance that a contract will be paid. It usually stays attached to the title until the contract ends or is paid off.</p>
<p>But homeowners don&#8217;t always know when a NOSI has been attached to their property. Cheung and others report that they only discovered the lien when they were facing tight timelines for home sales or refinancing. In many cases, those deals can&#8217;t go through while the NOSI is in place.</p>
<p>Feeling the pressure, Cheung eventually shelled out $11,000 to pay off the NOSI — much more than what similar water filter systems retail for online.</p>
<p>His experience is part of a trend that Ontario&#8217;s Public and Business Service Delivery Minister Todd McCarthy said has blown up into a &#8220;crisis&#8221; situation.</p>
<p>MARKETPLACEDespite charges against HVAC company, homeowners say they continue to lose millions in new contracts<br />
MARKETPLACE&#8217;Elaborate scam&#8217; leaves seniors with high-interest mortgages they didn&#8217;t want or understand<br />
To address what it calls the &#8220;abuse&#8221; of the NOSI system, the Ontario government recently passed changes to the Consumer Protection Act which include steps to make removing NOSIs easier and faster. It also recently concluded a consultations on possible additional steps and says it will act to prevent people from exploiting the NOSI system.</p>
<p>&#8220;Doing nothing is not is not an option,&#8221; McCarthy said in an interview with CBC&#8217;s The House. &#8220;We will take action to address this, to curtail it, and to stop the bad actors from abusing it.&#8221;</p>
<p>The CBC&#8217;s Marketplace has investigated the NOSI issue before, including Cheung&#8217;s case and the company he was involved with, Ontario Green Savings (OGS). Neither the company nor the lawyer representing it replied to CBC&#8217;s request for comment for this story. In the past, they&#8217;ve dismissed prior allegations against the company as unfounded.</p>
<p>A man in a suit stands beside a house.<br />
Lawyer Dennis Crawford says the use of NOSIs as part of rental equipment schemes is only growing. (Christian Paas-Lang/CBC)<br />
Lawyer Dennis Crawford, who has dealt with dozens of cases similar to Cheung&#8217;s, said there are common threads to many of them. Many of those victimized by NOSIs are elderly, or new Canadians, or others facing language barriers or challenges, he said. They sign up for rental contracts and — without their knowledge — a NOSI is registered against their title.</p>
<p>&#8220;The problem comes in when the homeowner tries to remortgage or sell their house,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Their lawyer would tell them, &#8216;Hey, there&#8217;s a lien on your house&#8217; — and this is almost always the first time the homeowner is hearing about it.</p>
<p>&#8220;They have to get the lien off title before the closing of their house sale, so they don&#8217;t have time to dispute this with Consumer Protection Ontario. They don&#8217;t have time to take the finance company to court and ask the court to delete the lien.&#8221;</p>
<p>MARKETPLACEMan alleged to be behind high-interest mortgage scam living large on social media<br />
Caught on camera: HVAC scam in action<br />
One of Crawford&#8217;s clients, Ian Craig, has several liens on his land title from work done on his home in Kitchener, Ont. Craig said he didn&#8217;t know the NOSIs would be applied.</p>
<p>&#8220;I don&#8217;t know how they&#8217;re allowed to make a lien like that. It&#8217;s just unbelievable. They put a lien on your house and you don&#8217;t even know it. And I think that&#8217;s disgraceful and that should be changed,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Several of the companies with registered NOSIs on Craig&#8217;s title did not reply to requests for comments. One company noted in a media statement that Craig had signed contracts indicating the company could place a NOSI on the title and that he was aware of his rights under consumer protection legislation.</p>
<p>Contracts provided by the company do include that language.</p>
<p>Craig said he was struggling with the loss of his wife at the time and did not really know what he was signing.</p>
<p>Situation getting worse, minister says<br />
Over 38,000 NOSIs were registered in Ontario last year alone. While not all of those are related to situations like Cheung&#8217;s, McCarthy said the overall abuse of NOSIs had worsened significantly.</p>
<p>&#8220;Often it&#8217;s a senior, a new Canadian, or a Canadian with language barriers or challenges [who] is duped into believing that they have to pay out some exorbitant amount of money. They&#8217;ll do so almost as a form of blackmail to get to clear up their title,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>&#8220;The notice of security interest has become a crisis just in the past year. And there&#8217;s a whole range of options that we can consider, and these include the option of complete abolition of notices of security interest as a tool for giving notice of the security interest.&#8221;</p>
<p>That&#8217;s the change Crawford said he would like to see.</p>
<p>&#8220;In my opinion, [NOSIs] are not supporting any legitimate commercial interest. They&#8217;ve outlived their usefulness. And it would be a lot better for consumers if, instead of making it easier for consumers to get these liens off title, just make it so that these liens can&#8217;t be put on title in the first place,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>A man wearing a suit and glasses sits behind a desk.<br />
The NDP&#8217;s consumer protections critic Tom Rakocevic says Ontario needs stronger consumer protection laws. (Christian Paas-Lang/CBC)<br />
The NDP, the provincial opposition in Ontario, supports that idea.</p>
<p>&#8220;Increasingly, more and more people that I speak to, whether it&#8217;s lawyers and consumers who have been harmed by this, refer to these types of liens as nothing more than extortion,&#8221; said Tom Rakocevic, the NDP&#8217;s consumer protections critic.</p>
<p>Rakocevic said the provincial government should strongly consider banning NOSIs entirely. He said Ontario lags behind other jurisdictions when it comes to consumer protection, and he has proposed the creation of an independent consumer watchdog.</p>
<p>A man in a suit stands in front of a flag.<br />
Ontario Minister of Public and Business Service Delivery Todd McCarthy says he&#8217;s considering all options when it comes to addressing NOSIs. (Christian Paas-Lang/CBC)<br />
McCarthy said it&#8217;s too soon to say what legal changes might emerge from the consultations and a decision will be made in the new year.</p>
<p>He said that while getting rid of NOSIs altogether is on the table, they do have some legitimate uses and the provincial government is focused on cracking down on their abuse.</p>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s that option [of banning NOSIs], and there&#8217;s many options between doing nothing and taking other steps,&#8221; he said. &#8220;And that&#8217;s the range of remedies that are available and we&#8217;ll look at all of them.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://api.sleepnumber.com/2023/12/17/ontario-is-looking-to-combat-lien-abuse-thats-costing-some-homeowners-big-money/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Object Caching 62/68 objects using Redis
Page Caching using Redis (User is logged in) 
Database Caching using Redis (Request-wide User is logged in)

Served from: _ @ 2023-12-20 02:14:40 by W3 Total Cache
-->